<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<feature id="KeY_Feature" label="KeY Feature" version="1.1.16" provider-name="KeY Project, University of Karlsruhe">

   <description url="http://www.key-project.org/">
      KeY is a tool that provides facilities for formal specification
and verification of programs within a commercial platform for UML based
software development. Using the KeY tool, formal methods and
object-oriented development techniques are applied in an integrated
manner. Formal specification is performed using the Object Constraint
Language (OCL), which is part of the UML standard. KeY provides support
for the authoring and formal analysis of OCL constraints. The target
language of KeY based development is JAVA CARD, a proper subset of JAVA
for smart card applications and embedded systems. KeY uses a dynamic
logic for JAVA CARD to express proof obligations, and provides a
state-of-the-art theorem prover for interactive and automated
verification. Apart from its integration into UML based software
development, a characteristic feature of KeY is that formal
specification and verification can be introduced incrementally.
   </description>

   <copyright url="http://www.key-project.org/download/LICENSE">
KeY - INTEGRATED DEDUCTIVE SOFTWARE DESIGN 
Copyright (C) 2001-2006 Universitaet Karlsruhe (TH), Germany,
Universitaet Koblenz-Landau, Koblenz, Germany,
and Chalmers University of Technology, Sweden.

Universitaet Karlsruhe (TH)
Institut fuer Logik, Komplexitaet und Deduktionssysteme
Am Fasanengarten 5
D-76131 Karlsruhe
Germany
and
Chalmers University of Technology
Department of Computing Science
Eklandagatan 86
SE-41296 Gothenburg
Sweden
   </copyright>

<license>     
NO WARRANTY
     
BECAUSE THE PROGRAM IS LICENSED FREE OF CHARGE, THERE IS NO WARRANTY
FOR THE PROGRAM, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW.  EXCEPT WHEN
OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND/OR OTHER PARTIES
PROVIDE THE PROGRAM "AS IS" WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED
OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF
MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  THE ENTIRE RISK AS
TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE PROGRAM IS WITH YOU.  SHOULD THE
PROGRAM PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME THE COST OF ALL NECESSARY SERVICING,
REPAIR OR CORRECTION.

IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN WRITING
WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MAY MODIFY AND/OR
REDISTRIBUTE THE PROGRAM AS PERMITTED ABOVE, BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR DAMAGES,
INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING
OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE PROGRAM (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED
TO LOSS OF DATA OR DATA BEING RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY
YOU OR THIRD PARTIES OR A FAILURE OF THE PROGRAM TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER
PROGRAMS), EVEN IF SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE
POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.
 </license>


   <url>
     <update label="Nightly Build Update Site" url="http://i12www.ira.uka.de/~key/KeYDists/KeY_Feature/"/>
     <discovery label="KeY Project" url="http://www.key-project.org/"/>
   </url>
  <requires>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.runtime"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.jdt.core"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.resources"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.jface.text"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.ide"/>
   </requires>

  <plugin id="KeYPlugin" download-size="0" install-size="0" version="1.1.16" unpack="false"/> 

  <plugin id="ProofVisualization" download-size="0" install-size="0" version="1.1.16" unpack="false"/> 

<!-- commented out until release of rotheVis Debug <plugin id="VisualDebugger" download-size="0" install-size="0" version="1.1.16" unpack="false"/> -->

  <plugin id="KeYExternalLibraries" download-size="0" install-size="0" version="1.1.16" unpack="false"/> 
  
  <plugin id="org.key_project.core" download-size="0" install-size="0" version="1.1.16" unpack="false"/> 

</feature>
