<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feature
      id="org.key_project.key4eclipse.starter.feature"
      label="KeY 4 Eclipse Starter Feature"
      version="1.0.0.qualifier"
      provider-name="KeY Project"
      plugin="org.key_project.key4eclipse.starter.product.ui">

   <description>
      A basic Eclipse extension to start KeY from within Eclipse.

For an optimal user experience it is recommended to use at least the following JVM memory settings:
-Xms128m
-Xmx1024m 
-XX:MaxPermSize=256m

The current settings can be inspected in the configuration tab of the installation details available in the "About Eclipse" dialog. They can be changed in the "eclipse.ini" file or by starting Eclipse with the following additional parameters:
-vmargs -Xms128m -Xmx1024m -XX:MaxPermSize=256m
   </description>

   <copyright>
      KeY - INTEGRATED DEDUCTIVE SOFTWARE DESIGN

Copyright (C) 2001-2011 Universitaet Karlsruhe (TH), Germany 
                        Universitaet Koblenz-Landau, Germany
                        Chalmers University of Technology, Sweden
Copyright (C) 2011-2013 Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, Germany 
                        Technical University Darmstadt, Germany
                        Chalmers University of Technology, Sweden

Karlsruhe Institute of Technology
Institute for Theoretical Computer Science
Prof. Dr. Bernhard Beckert / Prof. Dr. Peter H. Schmitt
Am Fasanengarten 5
D-76131 Karlsruhe
Germany

Technische Universität Darmstadt
Fachgebiet Software Engineering
Hochschulstr. 10
D-64289 Darmstadt 
Germany

Chalmers University of Technology
Department of Computing Science
Eklandagatan 86
SE-41296 Gothenburg
Sweden


WWW: http://key-project.org
e-mail: key@ira.uka.de
   </copyright>

   <license url="http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl/notice.html">
      This feature is distributed unter the license below. For the provided plug-ins different licenses might apply.

Eclipse.org Software User Agreement

Eclipse Foundation Software User Agreement
March 17, 2005

Usage Of Content

THE ECLIPSE FOUNDATION MAKES AVAILABLE SOFTWARE, DOCUMENTATION, INFORMATION AND/OR OTHER MATERIALS FOR OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS
(COLLECTIVELY &quot;CONTENT&quot;).  USE OF THE CONTENT IS GOVERNED BY THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS AGREEMENT AND/OR THE TERMS AND
CONDITIONS OF LICENSE AGREEMENTS OR NOTICES INDICATED OR REFERENCED BELOW.  BY USING THE CONTENT, YOU AGREE THAT YOUR USE
OF THE CONTENT IS GOVERNED BY THIS AGREEMENT AND/OR THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF ANY APPLICABLE LICENSE AGREEMENTS OR
NOTICES INDICATED OR REFERENCED BELOW.  IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS AGREEMENT AND THE TERMS AND
CONDITIONS OF ANY APPLICABLE LICENSE AGREEMENTS OR NOTICES INDICATED OR REFERENCED BELOW, THEN YOU MAY NOT USE THE CONTENT.
   
Applicable Licenses
   
Unless otherwise indicated, all Content made available by the Eclipse Foundation is provided to you under the terms and conditions of the Eclipse Public License Version 1.0
(&quot;EPL&quot;).  A copy of the EPL is provided with this Content and is also available at http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html.
For purposes of the EPL, &quot;Program&quot; will mean the Content.

Content includes, but is not limited to, source code, object code, documentation and other files maintained in the Eclipse.org CVS repository (&quot;Repository&quot;) in CVS
modules (&quot;Modules&quot;) and made available as downloadable archives (&quot;Downloads&quot;).
   
* Content may be structured and packaged into modules to facilitate delivering, extending, and upgrading the Content.  Typical modules may include plug-ins (&quot;Plug-ins&quot;), plug-in fragments (&quot;Fragments&quot;), and features (&quot;Features&quot;).
* Each Plug-in or Fragment may be packaged as a sub-directory or JAR (Java(tm) ARchive) in a directory named &quot;plugins&quot;.
* A Feature is a bundle of one or more Plug-ins and/or Fragments and associated material.  Each Feature may be packaged as a sub-directory in a directory named &quot;features&quot;.  Within a Feature, files named &quot;feature.xml&quot; may contain a list of the names and version numbers of the Plug-ins
  and/or Fragments associated with that Feature.
* Features may also include other Features (&quot;Included Features&quot;). Within a Feature, files named &quot;feature.xml&quot; may contain a list of the names and version numbers of Included Features.
 
The terms and conditions governing Plug-ins and Fragments should be contained in files named &quot;about.html&quot; (&quot;Abouts&quot;). The terms and conditions governing Features and
Included Features should be contained in files named &quot;license.html&quot; (&quot;Feature Licenses&quot;).  Abouts and Feature Licenses may be located in any directory of a Download or Module
including, but not limited to the following locations:

* The top-level (root) directory
* Plug-in and Fragment directories
* Inside Plug-ins and Fragments packaged as JARs
* Sub-directories of the directory named &quot;src&quot; of certain Plug-ins
* Feature directories
  
Note: if a Feature made available by the Eclipse Foundation is installed using the Eclipse Update Manager, you must agree to a license (&quot;Feature Update License&quot;) during the
installation process.  If the Feature contains Included Features, the Feature Update License should either provide you with the terms and conditions governing the Included Features or
inform you where you can locate them.  Feature Update Licenses may be found in the &quot;license&quot; property of files named &quot;feature.properties&quot; found within a Feature.
Such Abouts, Feature Licenses, and Feature Update Licenses contain the terms and conditions (or references to such terms and conditions) that govern your use of the associated Content in
that directory.

THE ABOUTS, FEATURE LICENSES, AND FEATURE UPDATE LICENSES MAY REFER TO THE EPL OR OTHER LICENSE AGREEMENTS, NOTICES OR TERMS AND CONDITIONS.  SOME OF THESE
OTHER LICENSE AGREEMENTS MAY INCLUDE (BUT ARE NOT LIMITED TO):

* Common Public License Version 1.0 (available at http://www.eclipse.org/legal/cpl-v10.html)
* Apache Software License 1.1 (available at http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE)
* Apache Software License 2.0 (available at http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0)
* IBM Public License 1.0 (available at http://oss.software.ibm.com/developerworks/opensource/license10.html) 
* Metro Link Public License 1.00 (available at http://www.opengroup.org/openmotif/supporters/metrolink/license.html)
* Mozilla Public License Version 1.1 (available at http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/MPL-1.1.html)

IT IS YOUR OBLIGATION TO READ AND ACCEPT ALL SUCH TERMS AND CONDITIONS PRIOR TO USE OF THE CONTENT.  If no About, Feature License, or Feature Update License is provided, please
contact the Eclipse Foundation to determine what terms and conditions govern that particular Content.

Cryptography

Content may contain encryption software. The country in which you are currently may have restrictions on the import, possession, and use, and/or re-export to
another country, of encryption software. BEFORE using any encryption software, please check the country&apos;s laws, regulations and policies concerning the import,
possession, or use, and re-export of encryption software, to see if this is permitted.
   
Java and all Java-based trademarks are trademarks of Sun Microsystems, Inc. in the United States, other countries, or both.
   </license>

   <url>
      <update label="KeY Indigo Updates" url="http://www.key-project.org/download/releases/eclipse/indigo"/>
   </url>

   <includes
         id="org.key_project.key4eclipse.feature"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <requires>
      <import feature="org.eclipse.platform" version="3.7.2"/>
      <import feature="org.eclipse.jdt" version="3.7.2"/>
   </requires>

   <plugin
         id="org.key_project.key4eclipse.starter.product.ui"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.key_project.key4eclipse.starter.ui"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

</feature>
